We gotta go.
我有事我先走了
Xiaoning,
筱柠
wait a minute.
你等一下
Sijing has something to tell you.
思靖有重要的事和你讲
I got something really crucial to get to.
我真的有很重要的事情
We'll talk tomorrow.
改天再说吧
Xiaoning!
筱柠
I know you still don't forgive me.
我知道你对我有心结
You don't accept my flowers
我给你送花不收
or pick up my calls.
打电话不接
I have no choice but to come here.
我只好当面找你聊
What now?
这可咋办
Xiaoning,
筱柠
what happened
当初的事情
was my fault.
是我做得不对
I'm sorry.
对不起
Can you give me another chance?
再给我一次机会好吗
We'd been together 7 years.
我们在一起七年了
I don't believe
我不相信
you've put me behind you.
你已经把我给忘了
I haven't.
我确实没忘
I knew it.
我就知道
We shared
我们在一起
7 years of memory.
有整整七年的回忆
Do you remember
筱柠你记得吗
I'd go with you to your major courses,
我每次陪你去上专业课
we'd make notes
我们会在一起
and ask questions?
做笔记问问题
The first time
还有你第一次
you visited our specimen room,
去我们的标本室
you got so scared that you couldn't sleep.
被吓得睡不着觉
You called me at mid night,
你半夜给我打电话
said you wanna go for a run.
说要去夜跑
In the senior year...
还有大四那年
Lu Sijing!
陆思靖
What's the point raking up the past?
回忆这些有意思吗
I said I haven't forgotten
我说我没忘
'cause that's my youth years.
是因为那些是我的青春
I'd never forget them.
我不会忘记的
But I don't love you any more.
但是我确实不喜欢你了
I don't
也对你
feel anything for you.
一点感觉都没有了
You...
你
don't love me any more.
不喜欢我了
Does it mean
那就是说
you'll never
你永远都不会
forgive me?
原谅我了是吗
Does it matter
你觉得
whether I forgive you or not?
我原不原谅你重要吗
Love and forgiveness
喜欢跟原谅
aren't the same thing.
根本就是两码事
It matters to me.
重要
You're in love with someone else.
你有喜欢的人了
Right?
对吗
That's my business.
这是我自己的事
Don't you worry.
跟你没关系
Let's go.
走了
Xiaoning!
筱柠
I'm not giving up!
我不会放弃你的
I'm off.
先走了
Take care, Mr. Ji.
纪总慢走
The flowers...
那个花
They're from him?
花是他送的吧
They are.
确实是他送的
But I thought...
但是 我以为是
Throw them out.
扔掉
I already did.
我已经扔了
Pick up.
接吧
See what he wants.
听听看他想说什么
Hello, Xiaoning.
喂 筱柠
I don't wanna give up on you.
真的不想放弃你
It was all my fault.
之前都是我的错
I'm so sorry.
我跟你道歉好吗
Please give me a second chance.
再给我一次机会
Xiaoning,
筱柠
are you listening?
你有在听吗
I'm sorry.
对不起
Don't be bothered
他说的话
by what he said.
你别放在心上
Okay?
好吗
The bids Mr. Shen made
沈总那几次叫价
were ingenious.
简直就是神来之笔
Pushed the bidding
直接把竞拍价
price right up
给顶了上去
and covered
直接覆盖了
the principal of the bad loan debt.
不良贷款的债权本金
Well done, Zhao,
行 赵哥
turning a bad loan into something good.
不良贷变废为宝
The award
先进个人
is well deserved!
非你莫属
Xu Li,
许力
low-key! Keep it in mind!
低调 低调 再低调
Yeah, low-key, I know.
低调 低调 我知道
Ms. Rao.
饶经理
Made all the way here, huh?
还专门来一趟啊
Aren't you gonna applaud me?
你不得给我鼓个掌啊
Sure.
可以
Special applause
特别的掌声
to the special you.
给特别的你
Alright, done. Now go back.
行了掌鼓完了回去吧
You're giving me a headache hovering here.
你站在这儿我心烦
Won't kill you to sit down.
坐着也不会死
It will kill me.
肯定会死啊
How can I sit
此时此刻
at such a special moment?
哪儿坐得下去呀
Kill you? Piece of cake.
死 死那太容易了
Xiaoning, go open that window
筱柠 去把那扇窗户
for Mr. Zhao.
给你小赵哥打开
He said sitting will kill him.
他坐着会死
Let him jump to his death then.
咱让他跳下去死
I think that window's jammed.
那个窗户好像是坏的姐
Oh, is it?
坏了
See?
看见没
Xiaoning works
现在小涂也算是我
for me sometime now.
半个徒弟了
But the rest of them
但是其他的
work.
都是好的
Are they?
是吧
That hurts.
扎心了
Women, huh.
最毒妇人心啊
Go back to your seat.
你回去吧你
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Try to be
上班时间呀
professional at work.
还是尽量要严肃一点
Sorry, sir.
不好意思
Mr. Ji.
领导
What is it?
什么事
I found some premium
刚才回来的路上
clients on my way
去了一趟园区
back from the Park.
发现了几个优质的客户
Was gonna talk to you about it.
正准备跟你汇报
Let's talk in my office.
办公室说吧
See?
看见没
Someone's switched allegiance.
倒戈了
Even Mr. Jiang couldn't tame him
之前咱们江总在的时候
when he's here.
都没能把赵方刚给收服
Yet Mr. Ji did it.
纪总竟然做到了
He's got something, hasn't he?
有点东西啊
It's...
这
You.
你
Come.
过来
Get this out of here.
赶紧给他拿走
Such bad luck.
晦气
Chop chop.
快走两步
Enough gloating.
不够他嘚瑟的
"I have some clients"
我有几个客户
"I need to talk to you about..."
跟你汇报一下
Want some?
姐你要点吗
I'm good. Thanks.
不用了我喝点水就行了
Your ex?
你前男友啊
He won't leave me alone.
阴魂不散的
Is that why
你就因为这个
you're not picking up his calls?
不接人家电话
You gotta remember
你别忘了
he's your ex,
他除了是你的前男友
but he's also your client.
他现在也是你的客户啊
Are you getting back together?
打算和好吗
No.
不打算
Then your conscience is clear.
那你就更问心无愧了
You've done nothing wrong.
你又没做错什么
Plus,
而且
you can't guarantee
你怎么能保证
you won't run into a client
在你以后的业务里面
who shares a
不遇到
special relationship
跟你有
with you.
特殊关系的人
Like your relatives.
比如你的亲人
exes,
前男友
or enemies.
仇人
What then?
那怎么办
You gonna hide from all of them?
这些关系都躲着
What about your job then?
业务不用做了
Hello?
喂
Hi, Xiaoning.
喂 筱柠
the Medical Banking Card
我们医院
service our hospital provides
银医一卡通的业务
is managed by your department, right?
是你们拓展部来做的吧
There's been a hitch.
现在结算出了点问题
Patients who failed to pay
结算不了的病人
are causing trouble.
都闹了起来
The president is pissed
据说院长现在非常生气
and thinking to replace you.
要把你们换掉
So...
你看你们
I see.
好 我知道了
We'll be on our way.
我们现在就赶过去
We will sort it out.
一定会解决
Get ready.
收拾一下
We're going to Renji Hospital.
跟我去一趟仁济医院
We've been notified.
我们也接到通知了
We're on our way.
马上过来
Bring the tech guy
把那个技术部门的人
along.
带着啊
Okay.
好
I'll bring some gift boxes too.
我再带点套装礼盒
Have the tech unit fix the servers.
让技术部门去处理后台
Wait a second.
稍等一下
Do what you do best
你只要发挥你
as a hall manager.
大堂经理的优势就行了
We've been waiting
我们这都等了
over half an hour.
半个多小时了
I can't get my medicine if I can't pay.
收不了费 取不着药
I only have four hours off work
就请了四个小时假
to see a doctor.
出来看病
Without my medicine,
但取不着药
how do I get back to work?
我回去怎么上班啊
Right.
对呀
If words got out,
这个消息一旦传出去
other banks would swoop in
其他银行肯定会来
for this deal.
抢这个单子
They are
在这一方面
ruthless.
他们都不是吃素的
Listen, you must
所以这边
handle this well.
你一定要处理好
I'll talk to the president.
我去搞定院长
Okay.
好
Wait a minute!
稍等一下
Our transaction system...
我们的结算系统
What's going on?
怎么回事
Quiet!
安静一下
Excuse me!
不好意思
Quiet, everyone, please.
大家安静一下
Can I say something?
听我说两句好吗
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm
我是
an employee from Dairui.
代瑞的员工
The hospital's system
这个医院的系统
is handled by our bank.
是我们银行负责
We're very sorry
今天出现这种情况
this has happened.
非常抱歉
My sincerest apologies.
我真诚地向大家道歉
We appreciate your understanding.
也希望大家可以理解
Our tech man
我们的技术人员
has confirmed that
已经确认过了
15 minutes
最多
at most,
十五分钟
the problem
最多十五分钟
can be fixed.
就可以解决
We've been waiting for ages.
我们都等多久了
Right, right.
是 是 是
We're very sorry.
非常抱歉 非常抱歉
As a token of our apology,
以表歉意
we're giving out
我给大家准备了
thermal cups.
联名的保温杯
We can
一会儿
pass them around later.
大家可以发一下
Who wants that?
谁要你那个保温杯
I need to pay
我得赶紧交费了
and go back to work.
回去上班啊我
How about this?
要不这样吧
Give me
你们把手里的
your prescriptions.
处方单给我
I'll give them to the pharmacy.
我先交到药房去
Once the system is back online
等系统修好了
you can pay,
大家交完钱
get your medicine and leave.
立马可以拿药走
Will that work?
可以吗
Hurry then.
那你快点吧
Okay. Thank you.
好 谢谢 谢谢
Hurry.
快点 快点啊
But I need to see a doctor.
不是我要找个医生啊
Okay. Okay.
好的 好的 好的
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Thanks for your understanding.
谢谢各位理解
Need a hand?
需要帮忙吗
No.
不用
Excuse me.
你好 你好女士
Are you the doctor
你是刚才给我看病的
who saw me earlier?
那个医生吗
Sure. Sure.
可以 可以
How do I take this medicine?
这个药怎么吃来着
You can't take this.
这个不能拿
This one.
这个拿
Two times a day.
一天两次
Ten hours in between.
间隔十小时以上
Is that all?
就这些了是吗
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢啊 谢谢大家
Take it with food,
随餐服用
to protect your stomach.
可以保护肠胃的
Okay.
好
But...
但是
the doctor told me
医生刚刚那边说我
there's no money in the personal account
什么医保卡个人账户
of my medical card.
怎么没钱
What does that mean?
这是什么意思啊
You might need
这个可能
to activate it.
需要激活一下啊
Okay, thanks.
好 谢谢
Here.
来
Don't worry.
大家不要着急啊
There's one for everyone.
都有 都有 都有
Come get it.
没拿到的朋友来
Excuse me.
医生您好
Please prepare
麻烦您
these medicines.
先把这些药配一下
They'll be collected when paid.
交完钱了以后再来取
Okay.
好
Thanks.
谢谢
Done.
修好了
Thank you so much.
辛苦了 辛苦了
Liu Xiaoqian.
刘晓倩
It's mine.
我的 我的
Here.
给您药
Ma Qiang?
马强是
So?
怎么样
How did it go?
解决了吗
I was a
怎么说我也是
hall manager for three years.
做过三年大堂经理的人
I can handle
这种事情
a situation like this.
我还是处理得好的
What about you, Jing?
静姐你呢
I'm the
怎么说
top woman of Section 1.
我也是拓展一部一姐啊
This is not my
这点风波
first time handling a disturbance.
我也还是见过的
As my soldier,
作为我带的兵
you've done pretty well.
做得不错
I heard
听说
your ex
这次你这个前男友
did you quite a favor.
帮了不少忙
Thank you for earlier.
今天谢谢你啊
You are welcome.
不用客气
Um...
那个
can I buy you a coffee?
我能请你喝杯咖啡吗
Not that I want
不是因为刚刚
something in return
我帮你一个小忙
'cause I did you a small favor.
就要什么回报啊
I just
我只是
need to talk to you.
有话想跟你说
It's almost time
这马上也到
to clock out.
下班的时间了
I'll let you decide.
怎么决定你看着办
See you, Doctor Lu.
陆医生下次见
Bye, Jing.
静姐再见
Okay then.
那行
I'll get changed.
那我先换身衣服
See you downstairs in a bit.
一会儿楼下见
Sorted?
解决了吗
Join me for dinner?
晚上一起吃饭
Maybe later.
晚一点吧
I need to
我跟陆思靖
talk to Lu Sijing.
还有话要说
Mom,
妈
have you received the money
这个月的生活费
for this month?
您收到了吧
Okay.
好
Yeah, I wired more.
对我多转了点
Bye.
拜拜
Ms. Rao.
饶经理
Working yourself too hard, no?
这么敬业呀
Coming back here
这都下班了
out of office hours.
还从医院赶回来
Getting some files.
拿资料
Oh, right.
对了
Congrats on rising
还没恭喜你
up to outstanding individual.
拿到个人先进
Are you...
你
complimenting me?
这是在夸我
Did I hear it right?
我没听错吧
See, I'm
你看我这
getting goosebumps.
汗毛都竖起来了
Well, I admit
这么多年了
you're not a nobody
你也不是职场上的
when it comes to work,
一个阿猫阿狗
but quite a
也算是一个
good match for me.
能配得上我饶静的对手
Congratulations.
恭喜呀
Fine.
行
I'll take that as a
那我就当你这句
compliment too.
也是夸我了
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Black coffee with lemon.
黑咖啡加柠檬
No mayo in your sandwich.
三明治没加蛋黄酱
Thanks.
谢谢你啊
You still remember.
还记得我的口味
I wasn't one
以前
to remember things back then.
我总是忽略很多事
But coming back
反倒这次回来
and seeing you
再遇见你
is making everything
过去的事情就像
come flooding back.
潮水一般地涌了出来
Things you like,
你的兴趣喜好
and what kind of life
你究竟想要
you want...
过什么样的生活
I only realize them now.
我现在才真正明白
That's 'cause
那是因为
you've realized your dream
你实现了梦想
of being a doctor.
当上了医生
So relationships have been
爱情就被提了档
moved up in their importance.
变得重要了一些
Xiaoning,
筱柠
I think you've misunderstood me.
你可能真的误会我了
I was all alone
那个时候
studying abroad.
我一个人在国外
I was super stressed.
压力也很大
But it doesn't mean I didn't care.
但并不代表我不在乎
Let's not
过去的事
dredge up the past.
咱们就别提了
You know this.
你知道的
The only way
医学生
for medical students to get in a
只有继续深造
hospital is to get further qualifications.
才有进医院的资格
I worked my ass off.
我拼尽了全力
Finally a university
终于有一家
abroad was willing to admit me.
国外的大学愿意录取我
They had the most advance technology
那里有最先进的技术
and the research projects
和我梦寐以求的
I dreamed of doing.
课题研究
I had to get
我必须得取得
the best grades
最优异的成绩
if I wanna stay after graduation.
毕业才能留下
That was my only chance.
那是我唯一的机会
I know.
我知道
And I understand.
也理解
Now that
现在
your dream has come true,
你梦想成真了
all your efforts
过去的那些努力
have paid off.
都没有白费
As an old classmate of yours,
作为老同学
I am glad for you.
为你高兴
Xiaoning,
筱柠
I know
我知道
I'm pestering you.
我这么缠着你挺烦的
But I wanna try with you again.
但我想再争取一次
Give me a chance,
给我一次机会
will you?
好吗
I'm sorry,
对不起啊
but I can't.
我不能给你这次机会
There's no future
我们两个
between us.
不可能了
I came 'cause
我 今天留下来
I wanna express my gratitude
也是想跟你说
to you.
谢谢你
Thanks for being there for me for 7 years.
谢谢你陪了我七年
We shared so many beautiful memories.
我们有太多美好的回忆
I hope
我希望
we can part on peaceful terms.
咱们好聚好散
I will
以后呢
turn a new leaf in my life.
我会有我自己新的人生
So will you.
你也一样
But it's over
但是我们俩
between us.
不可能了
Do you understand what I'm saying?
我的意思你能理解吧
Seems
看来
I really screwed up
我真的把我们的未来
our future.
搞砸了
If I hadn't left
如果当初我不独自离开
or if I had
又或者
come back earlier for you,
早点回来找你
maybe
或许
we would end differently.
我们的结果会不一样
Maybe.
或许吧
No one
没有一个人
will keep
会一直站在原地
waiting forever.
等另一个人的
Besides, I'm
况且我现在
in love with someone now.
有喜欢的人了
Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
Yes.
对
Office romance
我们银行
isn't encouraged in our bank.
不支持办公室恋爱
Not to mention we're in the same dept.
我们又是在同一个部门
It's not convenient to say it out,
不太方便告诉别人
but I should
但我今天觉得
let you know sooner.
我应该早点让你知道
Sorry,
不好意思
I gotta go.
我得先走了
Wish you
未来
all the best.
祝你一切顺利
Goodbye.
再见
What are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿啊
I come to see my mom.
来医院看看我妈
Finished?
都聊完了
Why do you look...
那怎么看起来
a little upset?
有点不开心啊
You know...
就是
the old days
想起了
still surround me.
以前的那些事情
I can't tell you that
我没办法跟你说
I've forgotten everything.
我全都忘记了
But please trust me,
但请你放心
I'll handle all well.
我一定会处理得很好的
It's all over now.
都过去了
Let's go see my mom.
一起去看看我妈
OK.
好
Let's go.
走
Oh, enough!
好了 好了
Okay.
好
So much you ordered!
怎么点了这么多呀
Didn't you have enough for dinner?
晚饭没吃饱吗
I didn't eat nothing at all.
我就没吃晚饭
I see.
没吃啊
That's good,
那正好
I'll go with you.
我陪你一起
These three flavors
这三个口味
are all your favorites, right?
都是你最爱吃的吧
How did you know?
你怎么会知道
Were you secretly following me then?
那时候有偷偷关注我
You're the school hunk.
你是校草吗
The girls
女生们
talked about you all the time.
会经常讨论议论你的
It's hard not to follow you.
我想不关注你都难
I remember
你这么一说
you're waiting for someone
我还真想起来了
at the entrance of my class,
好像是有那么一次
but you turned around
你在我们班门口等人
and ran away immediately
然后见到我之后
after seeing me.
调头就跑了
Was it possible that
莫非
you're waiting for me?
是在等我
No, no.
没有 没有
I wasn't.
我不是在等你啊
Then,
那没有等我
why did you run away?
跑什么呀
Well... I was indeed waiting for you.
我确实是在等你
But I was asked to.
但是我是受人所托
My classmate
我同桌
wanted me
她想让我
to send you a love letter.
帮她送一封情书给你
Is it good?
好吃吗
Are you happy with the delicious food?
吃到好吃的开心吗
What's the matter?
干吗呀
Why are you
你今天情绪
so down today?
怎么这么低落呀
Mom can see it.
妈都看出来了
Because of me?
怎么了跟我有关系吗
Nothing.
没什么
Don't just eat,
你别光顾着吃呀
I'm talking to you.
我在跟你说话呢
What did I do to upset you?
我哪儿得罪你了
I've been pondering a question.
其实我一直在想
We got married 'cause
我们俩的开始
we're compatible with each other.
是基于合适
What about now?
那现在呢
Is it still the same as before?
还和以前一样吗
Now,
现在
I think we're getting along
我觉得我们两个相处得
very well.
很愉快呀
But...
但是
Focus on the food.
吃包子
Stop talking further.
我不要听但是
Back to the school time,
就是这条街啊
many girls
那个时候
would've been
好多女同学
waiting on this street,
都在这儿等着
just to take a look at you.
就为了看你一眼
Sometimes,
有的时候
they even waited for half an hour.
要等半个小时呢
Oh, so,
那这么说
you're one of them.
你也是其中之一了
Of course not.
我可没有
I still haven't
我到现在都不能理解
figured out
她们为什么要
why they waited so long
等那么长时间
just to see you.
就为了看你一眼
Would that make you
看一眼
the boyfriend of one of them?
就能变成自己的了
Well, it didn't work.
这么说好像也是这样
Now I'm thinking,
我现在 在想
if they knew
要是 她们知道
we're together,
咱们俩在一起了
what would it be like
会是怎么样一个
a horrible scene?
血雨腥风的场景啊
I'm yours anyway.
反正都是你的了
They can't take me away.
她们抢不走
Since we're here,
既然都来到这儿了
why don't go inside and take a look?
要不进去看一眼
Can we?
进得去吗
We may be stopped by the security.
保安会不会不让啊
Come with me,
跟我来
be careful.
小心点
Where we are?
这个地方是
I once saw the most
我之前曾经在这个地方
beautiful sunset
看到过世界上
in the world here.
最美的晚霞
Oh, right!
我想起来了
You're sitting
你之前
right there before.
就坐在那儿
I thought you're gonna commit suicide,
我以为你要自杀呢
I ran over and hugged you.
我还过去抱住你
You told me
当时你还跟我说
that I must protect myself
一定要保护好自己
to enjoy a bright future.
才能看到雨过天晴
In fact,
其实当时
I wasn't...
我不是
Okay, stop here.
好了 好了 你别说了
I realized later that
我后来知道
you're not gonna jump off the building.
你不是要跳楼了
I were young then,
那个时候年纪小吗
acting like a know-all.
就是很中二
Such an embarrassing episode,
怎么这么糗的事情
you still remember it?
你到现在还记得呀
Of course.
当然要记得了
Xiaoning,
筱柠
actually...
其实
You don't need to comfort me.
你不用安慰我
I'm really good.
我真的没事
You know, you're a good girl.
你知道你的好
Lu Sijing is not the only one
其实不是只有一个人
who knows this.
才能看到
I've thought it over anyway.
我反正我都想清楚了
He always
他总是把
talked about
我们在一起很多年
the beautiful memories
还有他喜欢我很多年
we have had
我们有很多美好的回忆
over years.
挂在嘴上
And it's true.
也确实
He didn't do as he said
他没有按照他说的那样
to cherish our relationship,
珍惜我们的这段感情
to put it
把我们的感情
in the first place.
放在第一位
And now,
而我现在
for him,
已经对他
I don't have any feelings at all.
一点感情都没有了
It's really all over.
真的都过去了
For the past,
这些陈年往事
let's not talk about it anymore.
就不要再提了
Don't affect our
不要影响我们
mood now.
现在的心情
Come here.
来
Is it possible for us to see fireworks?
这会有人放烟花吧
Xiaoning,
筱柠
if I told you
如果我告诉你
I loved you silently for a decade,
我默默爱了你十年
would this
在你眼里
be a kinda
这是不是
pressure for you?
也算是一种压力呢
Forget it.
不过没关系
Let bygones be bygones.
过去的事不提
we can together
我们可以一起
make new memories.
创造新的回忆
Lu Sijing,
这个陆思靖
won't report me and Ji Yuheng
不会因为我拒绝他
'cause I reject him,
恼羞成怒
will he?
就告发我跟纪昱恒吧
Perhaps,
应该
it won't be that bad.
不会差劲到这种地步吧
But I can't
不过我也不能
gamble our future
把我们两个的前途
on him, right?
赌在他的身上吧
What if...
万一
Xiaoning, give it to me.
筱柠我来吧
No,
不用了
it's not my turn to clean today.
今天不是我打扫卫生
Are you sure?
确定吗
Sorry,
不好意思啊
I have a question for you.
我想跟你商量件事
How about
咱们两个
we make a rule
应该在家里
when at home?
制定一个约法三章
Look,
你看啊
we've been together for a short time,
我们本来相处时间就短
it's hard to understand each other.
很难理解对方的想法
Besides,
再加上有一层
you are my superior.
工作的关系
This makes misunderstandings easier.
就更容易产生误会
I think we should
我觉得我们两个应该
clarify our identities
重新定一个相处模式
between home
在家里跟工作上的身份
and work.
区分开
Otherwise,
要不然时间长了
it's easy to have problems.
很容易出现问题
It makes sense.
我觉得你说得有道理啊
They shouldn't be
感情和工作
mixed together.
确实不能掺和在一起
What's your plan?
那你先提
The negative emotions
如果我们在家里吵架了
caused by bickering at home
不能带到工作中去
cannot be brought to work.
打击报复这种事
I believe
我相信纪总
you won't retaliate
也不会做出来吧
against me at work, right?
带着情绪也不行
Of course not.
当然
And I have an idea too.
那我也提一条
Please.
好
After work,
下班之后
stop the red tape towards me.
不要再叫我纪总了
Any complaints
工作上有任何
you make about me
对我的不满
at work cannot be taken home,
不能把那个负面情绪
let alone
带到家里来
get angry with me
更不能因为工作的事情
because of it.
对我发脾气
Well,
那
we will call
以后工作中呢
Mr. Ji and Ms. Tu at work.
就是纪总跟小涂
Then at home,
那在家里就是
we're Tu Xiaoning
涂小姐
and Ji Yuheng.
和纪先生
Okay,
好
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Oh, no!
不对 不对
Ji Yuheng.
纪先生
Besides,
我们两个生活在
we live together.
一个屋檐下
Inevitably,
难免的
our living expenses will be mixed.
生活费就要混在一起
Logically,
那按理说
someone should hold the purse strings.
是应该有个人管钱的
It sounds like
听起来涂小姐
you're interested
是有心
in taking charge of the finances.
要操持财政大权了
I didn't mean it.
没有 没有 没有
I believe you're better
我是觉得这方面
at this than me.
你比我有经验
What's this?
这什么
These
这些啊
are all my demand deposit.
是我全部的活期存款
Some savings are for financial products.
还有一部分做了理财
I'll organize them later,
之后我整理一下
then send it to you.
再发给你
I'll link the pay card
一会儿我把工资卡
to your phone.
直接绑定到你手机上
The password
密码
is the same as the one for the door lock.
就跟家里密码锁的一样
Are you sure you want me to handle this?
你确定要我管钱
You don't want to?
不愿意啊
No.
没有
Well, then,
那如果我管钱的话
should I
我是不是应该
give you money every month?
每个月给你生活费啊
How much is appropriate?
那给多少合适呢
No expenses for housing,
住倒是不用花钱
I just need some
衣 食 行
for clothing,
再加上平时
food, transportation, and fishing
偶尔跟行长一起去钓鱼
with the President sometime.
这是我的全部开销
That's all.
你看着给就好
Don't you any part of it
平时没有什么
for entertainment?
娱乐项目吗
It should be considered.
娱乐费总要给一些吧
How much do you want?
多少合适呢
In this respect,
那我有没有娱乐项目
you have the final say.
就得看涂小姐你了
But seriously,
不过说真的啊
I really want to go somewhere
还真的挺想去一个地方
with you.
带着你一起
Where?
哪里
It's quite crowded.
人还挺多的
Ji Yuheng,
纪先生
have you been here often before?
以前经常来这儿
Nope. First time.
第一次
What a coincidence!
巧了
Me too.
我也是第一次
Oh, that's to say,
那是不是以后
whenever you go camping again,
每次要再来露营的时候
I'll be the one you think of.
都能想到我了
Let's go.
走
That's amazing.
你怎么这么厉害呀
You don't even need instructions
都不用看说明书
to get it right.
就能弄好
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm only
我有时候就想啊
younger than you a year.
我就比你小一岁
What do I always
为什么老觉得
feel like you're much more
你比我成熟好多啊
mature and knowledgeable
比我懂的事情也多
than me?
什么都会
If you think so,
如果一定要说
it may be
什么都会的话
'cause I have
那可能是因为
richer experience
我的社会经验
in various aspects.
比较丰富吧
Why don't you tell me?
你说来听听嘛
When I was very young,
其实我很小的时候
I've been
就开始自己
living on my own.
独立地生活了
I washed my clothes,
自己一个人洗衣服
and cooked by myself.
一个人做饭
When I was a freshman in uni,
我记得是大一的时候
my spare time
那时候我会利用
was used
课余的生活
for an internship,
去实习
in securities firms, banks,
什么证券公司呀
and investment banks.
银行 投行
I went to all of them.
这些我都去过
Later,
再到后来
I studied abroad as a graduate student,
研究生出国留学
I even interned
那时候还在华尔街
on Wall Street.
实习过一段时间
You can see,
所以一定要说的话
I have more social experience
那就是社会经验
than others.
确实比一般人丰富一些
You've
你把自己
got yourself so full.
安排得这么满啊
When you're in uni,
那你上大学的时候
didn't you have any
没有什么
leisure time?
业余生活吗
Reading books,
看书
listening to songs,
听歌
and playing basketball...
还有 打篮球
Do those count?
算吗
No,
不算
I mean,
我的意思是
playing games,
打游戏
going to Internet cafes and stuff.
去网吧之类的
Internet cafe?
去网吧
Yeah.
对呀
When I was in college,
我上大学那会儿
the boys in my class
我们班男生
used to go there
经常去网吧
paying games all night long.
包夜打游戏的
I didn't.
那我没有
Self-disciplined.
自律
Then,
那
at that time,
你上大学的时候
did you ever fall in love?
谈过恋爱吗
No, I didn't.
没有啊
Have you ever had feelings for anyone?
那有喜欢的人吗
You don't even have a favorite,
不会连喜欢的人
do you?
也没有吧
Of course, I do.
当然有
Then...
那
what happened?
为什么没谈恋爱
You didn't confess to her,
你没有跟她表白
and go after her?
没去追她吗
Actually,
其实
when I wanna do that,
当我想要告白的时候
I found she already had a boyfriend.
她已经有了男朋友了
That's why
所以
she never knew
她一直都不知道
you liked her.
你喜欢她
No, she didn't.
不知道
It's a pity.
可惜了
Why do you say that?
为什么说可惜了
I feel sorry
我是替那个女生
for that girl.
觉得可惜
You're so nice and good.
你这么好这么优秀
It's a shame to miss you.
错过了多可惜啊
You said I know everything,
你说我什么都懂啊
but I really don't deserve it.
可我是真的不敢当
I've always thought
其实我一直都觉得
I'm just an ordinary person.
我就是一个普通人
My father
我爸
died early,
早逝
and my mom is sick.
我妈妈她又生病
So there are many things
所以我不懂不会的东西
I don't know.
可太多了
After graduation,
毕业了以后
I have to keep learning
就必须得不断地积累
to accumulate experience.
不断地去学习
So there's no time
所以根本就
for anything else.
没有时间做别的
That's to say,
所以说呀
no one
不会有任何一个人
can success easily.
轻易地成功
You've achieved
你看看你
what you're doing now
你这个年纪
in a short period of time.
就做到了现在这个位置
It's all because
都是因为
you down to earth,
踩着自己的汗水
step by step.
一步一步往上走的
People
别人呢
only see
只看到了你
your bright and shiny side,
光鲜亮丽的一面
they don't see the pain behind you,
看不到你背后的辛酸
including me.
包括我
Thank you, Mr. Ji,
谢谢你啊纪先生
for telling me this.
愿意跟我说这些
I feel
我感觉
I understand you better.
我更了解你一点了
In fact, I'd like to thank you more
其实我更要谢谢你
for willing to know my story.
愿意了解我的这些故事
I'll do it.
我干了
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
when I accompanied you to meet clients,
我陪你见客户的时候
I thought you were a good drinker,
你酒量不是挺好的吗
you've only had a few beers.
这才喝几瓶啤酒啊
Are you kidding me?
真的是
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
didn't you bring two sleeping bags?
不是带了两个睡袋吗
I clearly remember
我明明记得
there're two.
带了两个睡袋啊
Where did the other go?
哪去了
C'mon...
什么呀
out in the middle of nowhere,
跑荒郊野外
we're here to share a bed.
来同床共枕了
You're awake.
你醒了
They seem to have some wine left,
你看他们好像还有酒
how about borrowing some?
要不借点
Don't be
你这人怎么
a wet blanket.
这么没眼色呢
They should be asleep.
人家都睡了
Go back now.
赶紧回去
Did you have a good day?
今天开心吗
Will you put it today
会把今天
in your memories?
放进你的回忆里吗
Good night.
晚安
Mr. Ji.
晚安纪先生
What's on your mind?
想什么呢
Good morning.
早
Why are you looking at me like that?
怎么这么看着我
Nothing.
没怎么
I'm not thinking anything,
我没想什么
don't be silly.
你不要瞎想
I thought
我还以为
you're regret about last night.
你遗憾昨天晚上
Why?
遗憾什么
Nothing to be regret.
有什么好遗憾的呀
Last night,
我昨天晚上
I lost my mind,
断片了
and I don't remember anything.
什么都不记得了
But,
不过我昨天晚上
I didn't lose my mind.
可没断片啊
I remember everything you said.
你说的话我可都有印象
I mean, all of it.
我记得你说的话
What did I say?
我说什么了
I'm nice,
你说我很好
dashing,
很帅
and meet your aesthetic preferences.
长在你的审美点上
I have charming eyes,
眼睛好看
and a nice nose
鼻子也好看
and mouth.
嘴巴也好看
Did I say that?
我这么说的吗
Impossible.
不可能
I would never say that.
我肯定不会这么说的
How could I?
我怎么能这么说话呢
Ji Yuheng, are you lying to me?
纪昱恒你是不是诈我呀
I'm angry!
我生气了
I'm hungry, I wanna go home for breakfast.
我饿了我要回家吃饭
Well, Tu Xiaoning would be like this
涂筱柠谈起恋爱来
when in love.
是这样的
Are you okay?
你好了没有
What took you so long to get sleeping bags?
拿个睡袋怎么这么久啊
I'll be right there.
马上啊
I'm coming.
来了啊